National Association for Public Continuing & Adult Education (NAPCAE) Records
National Association for Public Continuing & Adult Education (NAPCAE) Records
1976-1982
National Association for Public Continuing & Adult Education.
1 linear ft.
Records and other papers relating to the adult education organization. Minutes, conference material, correspondence, publications.
2684656
Biographical History
The National Association for Public Continuing Adult Education (NAPCAE) existed from 1975 to 1982. Its precursor organization, the National Association for Public School Adult Education (NAPSAE), was founded in 1952 to represent public school adult education and literacy programs within the Adult Education Association (AEA). In 1975 the name was changed to NAPCAE, the name under which it operated until 1982. In 1982 NAPCAE and AEA merged to create the American Association for Adult Continuing Education (AAACE).
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The National Association for Public Continuing & Adult Education (NAPCAE) Records contains meeting minutes, conference material, correspondence, publications, and other material relating to the organization.
Arrangement of the Collection
The consists of a single series, General files, containing conference and committee folders, constitution and by-laws, correspondence, legislative updates, policies and procedures, publications, and other material.
Related Material
has numerous collections in the area of adult education; please refer to for a complete listing. In particular, see the records of the predecessor organization,
National Association for Public School Adult Education (NAPSAE)
. Also, the
William Langner Papers
contains an extensive collection of the NAPCAE publications Swap Shop, Pulse and Techniques in the Printed material: Misc newsletters subseries.
Subject and Genre Headings
Adult education; National Association for Public Continuing & Adult Education.; Adult education -- United States.; Educators -- United States.; Elementary education of adults.; Constitutions.; Correspondence.; Directories.; Manuals (instructional materials); Memorandums.; Minutes (administrative records); Newsletters.; Reports.; Educators.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Albert Campbell, 2009.
Inventory
- General files
  - Board minutes, 1976-1977 (Box 1)
  - Committees, 1976-1978 (Box 1)
  - Conference info, 1974-1978 (Box 1)
  - Constitution, by-laws, reorganization committee, 1977-1979 (Box 1)
    See also Reorganization committee (Box 2).
  - Correspondence, 1976-1982 (Box 1)
  - General info, 1977; includes document on proposed changes to the American Society for Training and Development (ASTD) (Box 1)
  - [Legislative updates], 1978; found loose in the box, these appear to be alerts to membership on legislation affecting adult education (Box 1)
  - Meeting minutes, 1977 (Box 2)
  - MVAEA [Missouri Valley Adult Education Association] & IALL [Iowa Association for Lifelong Learning], 1978 (Box 2)
  - Planning survey, 1975 (Box 2)
  - Policies and procedures (Box 2)
  - Publications
    - Administrator's Swap Shop, 1976-1977 (Box 2)
    - NAPCAE Exchange, 1978-1980 (Box 2)
    - Pulse, 1978-1982 (Box 2)
    - Techniques, 1981-1982 (Box 2)
  - Reorg. committee, 1978 (Box 2)
    See also Constitution, by-laws, reorganization committee (Box 1)
  - Miscellanous, 1977-1978; photographs, clippings, correspondence, brochures from or about other adult education organizations (Box 2)